Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Newsletter Collection, 1910-2005 RL.00733
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- International Newsletter Series, 1929-2004
  - Europe
    - Germany
      - JWT Report Frankfurt, 1961, 2 folders (Box IN3)
        Agency and office news from West Germany. Published several times per year by the Frankfurt office, in German.
      - Letzter Blick auf 1983, 1983 (Box IN3)
        Focused on media information. In German.
      - Mahlzeit, 1972, 1975 (Box IN3)
        Office and light news from the Frankfurt office. In German.
      - [ Media Newsletter, 1994-1995: Removed to Restricted Newsletters, Box RN2] (Box IN4)
      - Meet-In, 1967 (Box IN4)
        In German.
      - Pressespiegel, circa 1984 (Box IN4)
        Agency news from Germany. In German.
      - Who is New?, circa 1983 (Box IN4)
        Personnel news from the Frankfurt office. In German.
    - Greece
      - Alector, 1964 (Box IN4)
        Agency and office news for Alector, JWT's affiliate in Greece (?). Published in Athens, in English.
    - Italy
      - [ Business Communication, 1993: Removed to Restricted Oversize Newsletters, Box ROV1] (Box IN4)
      - Dal mondo del mezzi/From the world of media, 1983 (Box IN4)
        Media news in Italy. In Italian.
      - Notiziario JWT-Italia, 1963 (Box IN4)
        General news. In Italian.
      - Qui...Thompson, 1963-1965 (Box IN4)
        Agency, office, and personnel news from Italy. Published quarterly by the Milan office, in Italian.
    - Netherlands
      - J. Walter Thompson Company News, 1961-1966 (Box IN4)
        Agency, client, and personnel news from the Netherlands. Issued bimonthly, 1961-1962; quarterly, 1962. Published by the Amsterdam office, in English.
      - Netherlands Newsletter, 1960 (Box IN4)
        Agency, office, and personnel news. In English.
    - Spain
      - [ JWT, 1976 Dec. 15: Removed to Oversize Newsletters, Box OV3] (Box IN4)
      - Notícias, 1980-1985 (Box IN4)
        Agency and personnel news from Spain. In Spanish.
      - Notícias de medios, 1984 (Box IN4)
        Media news in Spain. In Spanish.
    - Switzerland
      - [ JWT-Report, 1976: Removed to Oversize Newsletters, Box OV3] (Box IN4)
      - [ Spezialausgabe Sport, 1982: Removed to Oversize Newsletters, Box OV3] (Box IN4)
    - United Kingdom
      - [ 40 Something, 1993: Removed to Restricted Newsletters, Box RN2] (Box IN4)
      - Advertising Bulletin, 1949-1951, 3 folders (Box IN5)
        Agency, client, and personnel news (emphasis on issues in advertising). Published by the London office, possibly once per season.
      - Advertising Business, 1974-1979, 2 folders (Box IN5)
        Survey of articles focused on advertising industry-wide concerns. Published by JWT Information Services.
      - Book Bulletin, 1971 (Box IN5)
        Notices of additions to the Information Services library.
      - Book News, 1972-1990, 11 folders
        Reviews and abstracts of additions to the JWT Library. Published bimonthly by the London office.
        - 1972-1984, 1-7 of 11 folders (Box IN5)
        - 1985-1990, 8-11 of 11 folders (Box IN6)
      - The Case for Advertising: Newsletter, 1975 (Box IN6)
        Examines political and company background into the Case for Advertising project of the London office. For further information, see the J. Walter Thompson Co. Publications Collection, London Office Publications.
      - Consumer Affairs, 1980-1985, 6 folders
        - 1980-1984, 1-4 of 6 folders (Box IN6)
        - 1984-1985, 5-6 of 6 folders (Box IN7)
      - Contents List, 1967-1983 (Box IN7)
        Reports of JWT London Information Center library holdings, contents of recent trade journal articles available for reprint.
      - European Food News, 1969-1970 (Box IN7)
        News concerning the food retail industry. Continued by New Products and Sales Promotion in Europe.
      - Extracts, 1966-1968, 2 folders (Box IN7)
        Summaries of news reports.
      - Family Square, 1977 (Box IN7)
        Parody of Round the Square, from the London office.
      - Food and Drink News, 1976, 3 folders (Box IN7)
        News from the food and beverage industries, excerpted from published reports and the trade press.
      - Food News, 1975 (Box IN7)
        Excerpts from articles appearing in the food products industry trade journals.
      - General Interest, 1935 (Box IN7)
        Overview of office activity.
      - International Market News, 1977 (Box IN7)
        News concerning the food retailing industry.
      - Issue, 1986-1987 (Box IN8)
        Occasional papers addressing marketing and advertising issues in greater depth than other newsletters. Published by the London office.
      - JWT Bulletin, 1948-1950, 1970-1975, 2 folders (Box IN8)
        Headlines from various British newspapers, magazines, and business publications, addressing marketing, trade, and banking and other economic issues. Published by the London office.
      - JWT Information Services, 1977-1979 (Box IN8)
        Guides to resources in JWT Information Services departments.
      - [ JWT in Print, 1997-2001: Removed to Restricted Newsletters, Box RN2] (Box IN8)
      - JWT Market Reports, 1963-1966, 2 folders (Box IN8)
        Single-topic marketing research reports.
      - JWT Marketing News, 1968 (Box IN8)
        Extracts from food trade publications.
      - JWT Merchandising Newsletter, 1962 (Box IN8)
        Merchandising news and issues in Britain. Published by the London office.
      - JWT/BMRB News, 1950-1951 (Box IN8)
        Agency, client, and personnel news for JWT and its associate, the British Market Research Bureau. Published monthly by the London office.
      - New Products, 1975 (Box IN8)
        Brief notices of new products from clients.
      - New Products and Sales Promotions in Europe, 1971-1972 (Box IN8)
        Continues European Food News.
      - Round the Square, 1951-1986, 31 folders
        Agency, client, and personnel news for JWT and its associate, the British Market Research Bureau. Published monthly (occasionally bimonthly) by the London office. Continues JWT/BMRB News.
        - 1951-1957, 1-3 of 31 folders (Box IN8)
        - 1957-1970, 4-20 of 31 folders (Box IN9)
        - 1970-1986, 21-31 of 31 folders (Box IN10)
      - Sales Promotion, 1970-1975 (Box IN10)
        Merchandising news.
      - Sales Promotion & New Products in Great Britain, 1975-1978, 2 folders (Box IN10)
        Primarily extracts from trade journal articles. Combines Sales Promotion and New Products journals.
      - Scrip, 1973 (Box IN10)
        Focuses on the pharmaceutical industry.
      - Trends, 1966 (Box IN10)
        Trends in fashion, jewelry, discotheques, buildings, and furniture and furnishings. Published by the London office. Does not address JWT news.
      - [ Vantage, 1996-1997: Removed to Restricted Newsletters, Box RN2] (Box IN10)
      - [ Whistling Sausage, 1993-2003: Removed to Restricted Newsletters, Box RN3] (Box IN10)
  - Asia/Pacific/Africa
    - General
      - [ Thompson Way, 1994-1997 and undated: Removed to Restricted Newsletters, Box RN3 (Issues for years 1994-1995 removed to Restricted Oversized Newsletters, Box ROV1)] (Box IN11)
    - Australia
      - Australian News, 1959 (Box IN11)
        Agency, client, and personnel news from Australia. Covers Sydney and Melbourne offices.
      - Intercomm: A Marketing/Management Digest from the J.W.T. Sidney Information Centre, 1977 (Box IN11)
        Australian and international business news. Does not cover JWT affairs.
      - JWT Communique, 1977 (Box IN11)
        Office and personnel news. Covers Sydney and Melbourne offices.
      - JWT Media Information, 1977 (Box IN11)
        Adelaide, Brisbane, Melbourne, and Perth surveys of television programming and viewership.
      - JWT News, early 1970s (Box IN11)
        Single issue covers Don Johnston's trip to Melbourne and Sydney offices.
      - Market Facts, 1961-1963 (Box IN11)
        Each issue focuses on a single topic.
      - This Week--Info Centre, 1977 (Box IN11)
        Australian business news. Does not cover JWT affairs.
      - [ Viewpoint, 1992-1993: Removed to Restricted Newsletters, Box RN3] (Box IN11)
    - Hong Kong
      - Newsletter, 1984 (Box IN11)
        Light office and personnel news. In English.
    - India
      - HTA Today, 1988-2003 (1991-2003 folder removed to Restricted Newsletters, Box RN3) (Box IN11)
        General news about Hindustan Thompson. In English.
      - Indian File, 1968-1972 (Box IN11)
        Agency, client, and personnel news from India. Published monthly by the Bombay office, in English; also covers Calcutta, Madras, and New Delhi offices.
      - J.W.T. Club Bulletin, 1958 (Box IN11)
        Light office and personnel news from the Bombay office. In English.
      - Looking Ahead, 1956 (Box IN11)
        Agency, client, and personnel news from India. Covers Bombay, Calcutta, Madras, and New Delhi offices. In English.
      - [ Promotion, 1976: Removed to Oversize Newsletters, Box OV3] (Box IN11)
    - Indonesia
      - The Indonesia Letter, 1970 (Box IN11)
        Indonesian political, economic, and military news. Does not cover JWT affairs. Published by P.T. Thomertwal Advertising, JWT's affiliate in Jakarta, in English.
      - Newsletter, 1975 (Box IN11)
        Office and market news. Published by P.T. Thomertwal Advertising, JWT's affiliate in Jakarta, in English.
    - Japan
      - Tokyo JWT News, 1967 (Box IN11)
        Agency, client, and personnel news from Japan. Published by the Tokyo office, in Japanese.
    - Malaysia
      - Now Read This: The Newsletter of PTM Thompson Advertising, 1977-1978 (Box IN11)
        Office and personnel news. Published by JWT's affiliate in Kuala Lumpur. In English.
      - PTM Thompson, 1977 (Box IN11)
        Office, client, and personnel news. In English.
    - Philippines
      - JWT Newsletter, 1969 (Box IN11)
        Office and personnel news from the Philippines. Published weekly by the Manila office, in English.
    - South Africa/Rhodesia (Zimbabwe)
      - JWT Circle, 1968-1970, 1972, 2 folders (Box IN11)
        Agency, client, and personnel news from JWT in South Africa and Rhodesia. Published bimonthly (quarterly in 1972), in English. Covers Johannesburg, Capetown, Port Elizabeth, Durban, and Salisbury (Harare), as well as JWT activities elsewhere in southern Africa.
      - JWT Media Bulletin, 1976 (Box IN11)
        Focus on broadcast media advertising. In English.
      - JWT Newsgram, 1974-1976 (Box IN11)
        Agency, client, and personnel news from JWT in southern Africa. Covers Johannesburg, Capetown, and Salisbury offices. In English.
      - [ Key Response, 1992-1993: Removed to Restricted Newsletters, Box RN3] (Box IN11)
      - [ Media Update, 1992: Removed to Restricted Newsletters, Box RN3] (Box IN11)
      - News Letter, 1968 (Box IN11)
        Agency news in South Africa and Rhodesia. No South African offices specified. In English.
- Oversize Newsletters, 1930-1982
  - Main Newsletter Series, 1930-1931
    - J.W.T. News, 1930-1931 (Box OV1)
  - Domestic Newletter Series, circa 1942-1945, 1978-1986
    - Offices Subseries, circa 1942-1945, 1978-1986
      - Detroit
        - Directions, undated (Box OV2)
      - New York
        - 402 Lex, 1982-1986 (Box OV2)
          News specific to the New York office building. Sometimes inserted into issues of New York Thompson.
        - JWT Front and Center, circa 1942-1945 (Box OV2)
          Bulletin of JWT employees serving in the military during World War II.
        - New York Thompson, 1978-1982, 2 folders (Box OV2)
          Office, agency, client, and personnel news.
  - International Newsletter Series, 1976-2004
    - Europe, 1976, 1982
      - Spain
        - JWT, 1976 Dec. 15 (Box OV3)
          Single issue celebrating 10th anniversary of JWT España. In Spanish.
      - Switzerland
        - JWT-Report, 1976 June (Box OV3)
          Published by the Zürich Office. In German.
        - Spezialausgabe Sport, 1982 (Box OV3)
    - Asia/Pacific/Africa, 1978
      - India
        - Promotion, 1978 (Box OV3)
          Newsletter of AAA India. In English.
- Restricted Newsletters
  Newsletters are closed to non-JWT users for 15 years from the date of publication. See also Restricted Oversize Newsletters.
  - Domestic Newsletter Series
    - Offices Subseries
      - Atlanta
        - Owl and the Lamp, 1992-1993 (Box RN1)
          Light news and humor. Published at irregular intervals.
      - Chicago
        - Talker, 1992-1998, 6 folders (Box RN1)
          Light office news. Published biweekly. Continued by Talker Online.
        - Talker Online, 1998-1999, 3 folders (Box RN1)
          Electronic newsletter. Published monthly. Continues Talker.
      - Detroit
        - Ford/Thompson Times, 1999-2005 (Box RN1)
          Office, client, and personnel news. Also entitled Ford/JWT Times
        - JWTimes, 1995-1998, 2 folders (Box RN1)
        - News from J. Walter Thompson Detroit, 1991-1994 (Box RN1)
      - New York
        - Target, 1991-1992, 1994 (Box RN1)
          Focus on new business in North America.
      - San Francisco
        - Change, 1995-1996 (Box RN1)
          Focus on brand communications.
    - Divisions Subseries
      - JWT Specialized Communications
        - Live Wire, circa late 1990s-2000 (Box RN1)
          Focus on the mature market.
    - Other Newsletters Subseries
      - In the News, 1995, 1998-1999 (Box RN2)
      - J. Walter Thompson Kid Stuff, 1994-1995 (Box RN2)
        Collection of Information and Shared Experiences from the World of Kids. Published bimonthly.
      - J. Walter Thompson World, 1991-1992 (Box RN2)
      - JWT Greenwatch, 1991-1993 (Box RN2)
        Broadly focused on the green movement in business and environmental protection.
      - J.W.Trends, 1990-1994 (Box RN2)
      - White Papers, 1992-1993 (Box RN2)
      - World News Roundup, 1997-1999 (Box RN2)
        News summaries in both paper and email formats.
  - International Newsletter Series
    - Latin America
      - Mexico
        - Bitácora, 1992 (Box RN2)
          Internal publications focused primarily on account news. In Spanish.
    - Europe
      - General
        - Commodore, 1993-1995 (Box RN2)
          Survey of news from various European offices. In English.
      - Germany
        - Media Newsletter, 1994-1995, 4 folders (Box RN2)
      - United Kingdom
        - 40 Something, 1993 (Box RN2)
          General company news. Published monthly.
        - JWT in Print, 1997-2001 (Box RN2)
          Highlights published work by JWT employees.
        - Vantage, 1996-1997 (Box RN2)
          Each issue focuses on a different topic.
        - Whistling Sausage, 1993-2003, 2 folders (Box RN3)
          Satirical view of London Office life.
    - Asia/Pacific/Africa
      - General
        - Thompson Way, 1994-1997 and undated (Issues for years 1994-1995 removed to Restricted Oversized Newsletters, Box OV5) (Box RN3)
          General news about JWT Asia/Pacific operations. In English.
      - Australia
        - Viewpoint, 1992-1993 (Box RN3)
          Focus on media research and consumer behavior. Published quarterly.
      - India
        - HTA Today, 1991-2003 (Box RN3)
      - South Africa/Rhodesia (Zimbabwe)
        - Key Response, 1992 (Box RN3)
          News about new products, research and innovations in campaign strategies. In English.
        - Media Update, 1992 (Box RN3)
          Focus on broadcast media. In English.
- Other Oversize Newsletters
  15-year contractual restriction for materials in this series expired in 2019.
  - Domestic Newsletters Series
    - Offices Subseries
      - Chicago
        - Listener, 1993 (Box ROV1)
          Focus on consumer attitudes and behavior.
  - International Newsletters Series
    - Europe
      - General
        - Out of the Blue, 1998-2004 (Box ROV2)
          Glossy magazine of general European account news.
      - Italy
        - Business Communications, 1993 (Box ROV1)
          Published by JWT Business Communications. In Italian.
    - Asia/Pacific/Africa
      - General
        - Thompson Way, 1994-1995 (Box ROV1)
          Publication of JWT Asia-Pacific. In English.